骇翼 损伤报告？
Dreadwing. Damage report.
所有重要系统都严重受损 威震天陛下
We have suffered critical damage to all major systems, lord Megatron.
需要一段时间才能让飞船重新起飞
It will be some time before we can get the ship airborne.
声波…
Soundwave.
看来是一个汽车人弄坏了我的船
So it was an Autobot who crippled my vessel.
他们必定会抓住我们的破绽 发起奇袭
They will move quickly to exploit any perceived weakness.
他们显然不会蠢到发动正面攻击吧 我的君王？
Surely they're not foolish enough to launch a direct assault, my liege.
自从我们上次见面后 擎天柱不再那么心慈手软了…
Optimus has grown decidedly more ruthless since our last encounter.
威震天陛下 作为您的医生
Lord Megatron, as your physician
对此我表示强烈反对
I strongly advice against this.
尽管黑暗能量的再生能力十分可观
Dark Energon's regenerative properties are impressive
但这副作用…
but the side effects...
我们无从得知它会对飞船造成什么伤害
there is no telling how it might impact the ship.
黑暗能量就在我身体中流淌
Dark Energon courses through my veins.
把它输给战舰将使我能操纵战舰
Infusing the warship will enable me to manipulate the craft as if we are one.
我们合二为一 便可摧毁擎天柱
And together, we shall crush Optimus Prime.
那些机器昆虫突然退下了
But when the Insecticons suddenly backed off
我意识到我应该离动力核心很近
I got inspired by my proximity to the power core...
于是我发挥特长…
... and did what I do best.
你把威震天的飞船搞得一团糟 简直就像旅馆房间里的摇滚明星！
You trashed Megatron's ride like a rock star in a hotel room.
我们应该乘虚而入 发动进攻
We should hit the Cons right now while they're vulnerable.
尽管威震天的飞船迫降了
Megatron's warship may be grounded
但别忘了对手的人数是我们的几百倍
but let's not forget that we remain vastly outnumbered.
特别是他又把一窝虫子收入麾下…
Especially since he has added the insecticon hive to his ranks.
要不我呼叫空中打击吧
Then maybe it's time for me to call in an air strike.
或许我们应该考虑一些非常手段 福勒探员
Or for us to consider more extreme measures, Agent Fowler.
火种剥离器？
The Spark extractor?
擎天柱 你确定要这么做？
Optimus, are you certain you want to travel down this path?
虽然我十分不情愿动用这种武器
While I am deeply reluctant to deploy a weapon of this caliber
尤其是霸天虎设计的武器…
especially one forged by Decepticon hands
…但这或许是我们结束战争的唯一办法…
this may be our only chance to end the war
…一劳永逸
once and for all.
是的 我感觉得到！
Yes. I can feel it!
擎天柱 我在霸天虎的坠机处监测到一个巨大的能量信号！
Optimus, I'm detecting a massive energy spike at the Decepticon crash site.
那是黑暗能量
It appears to be dark Energon.
汽车人 变形出发！
Autobots, transform and roll out!
等等 擎天柱 既然你要使用超级武器\N来与霸天虎作最终决战
Hold on, Prime. If you are gonna deploy some kind of super weapon in the final showdown with the Cons
那么 我有义务代表地球人见证这一刻！
it's my job as a representative of planet Earth to bear witness.
我的自由女神像啊！
Sweet lady Liberty.
擎天柱 你从不辜负我的期待
Optimus, you never disappoint.
大黄蜂 趁现在！
Bumblebee, now.
阿尔茜 隔板 吸引火力！
Arcee, Bulkhead, draw their fire.
一旦启动火种剥离器
Once you launch the Spark extractor
立即撤出其有效半径
be sure to clear its radius before it can activate.
大黄蜂！
Bumblebee!
我来！
Mine!
我怎么不知道舰上配备了静止射线！
I didn't realize this ship was equipped with a stasis beam.
去斐济过圣诞节的愿望要泡汤了
So much for christmas in Fiji.
嗯？
Huh?
火种剥离器
The Spark extractor!
靠近点 让我取回本属于我的东西
Guide us closer so that I may collect what belongs to me
然后摧毁汽车人！
and destroy the Autobots.
作战失败 呼叫医疗救援
Team's down. Requesting medevac.
什么？你要去哪儿？我说靠近！
What?! Where are you going? I said closer!
威震天陛下 飞船看上去像在自动驾驶
Lord Megatron, the ship seems to be navigating itself.
手动操控！
Override.
系统不接受手动控制！
The system's are bypassing manual contr... ohhh!
看上去飞船有了自己的意识！
It appears the ship now possesses a will of its own.
不可能！
Impossible!
查出故障原因 然后修好它！
Trace the problem to its source and fix it!
不许篡改我的系统
Do not tamper with my systems!
我只警告一次！
This will be your only warning!
警告？！
Warning?!
我的任务优先执行
My mission assumes priority.
任何干扰我的塞博特恩人都将被摧毁…
Any Cybertronian who interferes will be neutralized.
我自己的飞船竟敢用威胁的口吻和我说话？
My own vessel dares to address me in threatening tones?!
而且它似乎比我们更擅长破译铁堡计划的数据库
It also seems to be doing a better job of decoding the project Iacon database than we were.
它已经又解出了一组坐标！
It's already deciphered a new set of coordinates.
按我们目前的航向推断
And judging by our current course
那正是战舰要去的地方
that is precisely where the ship is headed.
那正是我想要的 你看
As I desire. You see,
这艘战舰不过是我个人意志的延伸
this warship is nothing more than an extension of my very will.
你的个人意志不值一提！
Your will is nothing.
铁堡的遗产将属于我！
The Iacon artifact will belong to me.
我是威震天陛下！我命令你停止运行！
I am Lord Megatron! I command you to cease operations!
你权威不再了
You are no longer in command.
不管用什么手段
Regain control of this vessel
夺回战舰的控制权！
by any means necessary.
全体船员 切断主能源
All hands, cut power to the mainframe
断开数据继电器 马上行动！
and disconnect data relays now!
他们还活着
They're alive.
但我从没遇到过这种类型的静止状态
But I've never encountered this form of stasis lock.
虎子们正在穿越大西洋！
The 'cons are crossing the Atlantic
沿着最短的路线前往北美地区！
making a beeline for North America.
等等 我们能追踪他们？
Wait. We can track them?
他们为什么没有照常开启隐形装置？
Why aren't they cloaked, like usual?
一切都太不正常了
None of this makes a lick of sense.
他们离我们近在咫尺 却转身飞走了！
They had us in their cross hairs, but the 'Cons just took off.
他们连火种剥离器都没拿！
They even bailed on that Spark extractor thingy.
如果飞船没有隐形
Well, if the ship isn't cloaked
或许通讯频道也开着 那么…
maybe the communications relay's open
怎么着 你的意思是咱干脆给老威打个电话
- and...\N- Yep, yep. Are you suggesting that we just call Megatron
问问他上面发生了什么？
and ask him what's happening up there?!
威震天陛下 计算机破解了另一个坐标
Lord Megatron, the computer has decrypted a second set of coordinates.
或许我们应该允许它继续…
Perhaps we should permit it to continue.
我不需要谁的准许
I do not require permission.
汽车人基地欧米伽一号呼叫霸天虎战舰！
Autobot outpost Omega One to Decepticon warship.
威震天 请回话
Megatron, please respond.
这场叛变到此为止了！
This mutiny ends now.
威震天
Megatron.
威震天已被革除了领导地位
Megatron has been relieved of his command.
你是谁？
Who is this?
你是谁！
Who is this?!
你控制了霸天虎战舰？
Have you taken control of the Decepticon vessel?
我就是战舰！
I am the vessel.
任何敢于干涉我任务的塞博特恩人都将被摧毁
Any Cybertronian who interferes with my mission will be neutralized.
什么任务？
What mission?
首要任务
Priority one
破译铁堡数据库 回收霸天虎科技
decrypt Iacon database and recover Decepticon technology.
为了什么目的？
For what purpose?
它挂机了？不礼貌！
It hung up? Rude.
岂止不礼貌？一艘巨大的战舰在四处游荡
Rude?! There's a giant spaceship flying around
搜集霸天虎的大规模杀伤性武器！
collecting Decepticon weapons of mass destruction!
这艘巨大战舰上的霸天虎都被消灭了
Wha... a giant spaceship filled with neutralized Decepticons.
什么意思？
Point?
这或许是我们登舰下载铁堡数据库的唯一机会
This could be our only chance to slip aboard and download the Iacon database.
这样擎天柱就能破译它！
So Optimus can decode it.
绝妙的主意 我会潜入霸天虎的飞船
Ingenious. I will infiltrate the Decepticon warship.
这样就不妙了 霸天虎是什么下场你都看到了
Not ingenious. You saw what it did to the Decepticons.
说不定威震天都难保！
And probably Megatron, too.
还有领袖卫队
And team Prime.
不过？那艘战舰明明可以置我于死地
But that tub had me dead to rights
我却保住了老命！
and I'm still breathing.
那艘船或许看不到人类
The ship may be blind to humans.
很好 福勒探员
Very well, Agent Fowler.
不过一旦有任何险情
But at the first sign of trouble
我会立即将你传送回来！
I am bridging you right back here.
现在 为了下载数据
Now, in order to download the database
你需要一个相匹配的传输磁盘
you will need a compatible transfer drive.
什么？
A what?
他还需要技术支持
He'll also need tech support.
还有后援！
And backup.
福勒呼叫基地 我们进来了
Fowler to base. We're in.
很好 任意一个控制台都可以访问数据核心
Good. Their data core should be accessible from any console.
这…这儿有一个！
H-here's one.
击倒被击倒了！
Doc Knock is knocked out.
看 战舰解出了两组铁堡坐标！
Look. The ship's decoded two sets of Iacon coordinates.
三个！咱们赶快拿了闪人
Three! Let's rip and run.
这里是接口！
There's the port.
嗯 为什么这艘战舰在飞向曼哈顿？
Um, why is the warship heading for Manhattan?
因为那里是第一组坐标锁定的地点？
Because that is where first set of coordinates are located.
塞博特恩的遗物怎么可能在美国纽约城？
What would a relic from Cybertron be doing in the Big Apple?
铁堡的圣物在很久以前失落到了地球上 福勒探员
The Iacon relics landed on Earth eons ago, Agent Fowler
远早于城市建立的时间
long before the city was built atop it.
也就是说战舰为了得到这个
Which means if the ship wants this one...
得推掉一些大楼
it may have to move some buildings out of the way.
我们的任务变得复杂了
Our mission just got complicated.
我们要怎么阻止战舰？
How do we deter this ship?
我建议销毁导航模块
I would advise disabling the navigation module.
调出主导航菜单！
Call up the main navigation menu.
那里！
There.
让开 孩子！
Step aside, son.
福勒探员？！
Agent Fowler!
发现系统访问
System access detected.
严禁任何干涉行为！
Interference will not be tolerated.
那边！
There.
快现身！
Reveal yourself.
它没有看到我们！
It doesn't see us.
暂时的！
Yet.
战舰没有扫描碳基生命体
The ship must not be scanning for carbon-based life-forms.
但是一旦它扩大搜索频率…
But once it widens its search parameters...
我们就完蛋了
We're toast.
我把你们传送回来！
I'm bridging you back.
不！纽约成千上万的生命正在生死关头
No. There are millions of lives at stake in New York
而我们三个是唯一可以阻止这件事的人
and we three are currently the only ones who can do anything about it.
别勉强自己 杰克
You're out of your element, Jack.
从读数上看 还有战舰恢复的速度
These readings, the ship's rapid recovery...
都说明威震天用了黑暗能量来修复它
all point to the fact that Megatron employed Dark Energon to repair it.
等等 如果说战舰是靠黑暗能量驱动的
Hold on. If you're saying the ship is fueled by dark Energon
那我们可以切断供给 不是吗？
we can dump it, right?
嗯…你们需要关闭战舰的能量注入器
You'll need to reserve the warship's Energon infuser.
顺着天花板上的主管道前进
Follow the main overhead conduits.
就能到达能量核心
They'll lead you to the power core.
威震天也准备这么干！
Megatron had the same idea.
这么说我们走对了
Then we're on the right track.
能量输出闸门只能手动操作
The Energon injection valve can only be operated manually.
手动？
- Manually?!\N- Manually?!\N- Manually?!
托我上去！
Give me a boost.
我被外星生命体入侵了！
I am infested with alien life-forms!
啊哦 我们完了！
Uh-Oh. We just got made.
清除一切寄生虫
All parasites will be eradicated!
嘿！这里！
Hey! Over here!
杰克 不！
Jack, no!
快跑！
Run for it!
太慢了！
Too slow!
动力严重不足
Critical power drain.
我…才是…老大！
I am... in... command.
准备…
Prepare to be...
受死…
neutralized.
快跑
Run.
感谢火种源
Thank the Allspark.
救护车
Ratchet!
开启环陆桥！
Fire up the Ground Bridge!
站稳了 士兵！
On your feet, soldier.
还有海狸还有海象还有鸭子还有老奶奶！
And beavers and ducks and walnuts and... grandma?
才下载了这么点？
That's all that's been downloaded?!
铁堡档案肯定很庞大！
The Iacon file must be huge!
太棒了！
Sa-weet!
快 我们快走！
Come on! Here's our ride!
杰克？
Jack?!
送福勒出去
Get Fowler out of here.
有一点总比什么都没有强
Some is better than nothing.
拿不到磁盘我是不会走的
I'm not leaving without that drive.
说“啊”
Say "ahh."
我来提点不同的诊断意见
I'm here to offer a second opinion.
威震天陛下 我…
Lord Megatron, I...
你让他们跑了！
You let them escape...
还带着重要的情报！
with vital intelgence.
尽管下载到的铁堡数据不完整
The download of the Iacon database may have been incomplete
但我们已经拥有了战舰所破译的四个坐标
but we now possess four sets of coordinates decoded by the ship.
那我们必须得尽快行动
Then we must act quickly
因为威震天也有这四个坐标
for Megatron possesses the same four sets.
并且 他会毫不犹豫地夺取那里的超级武器…
And he will not hesitate to obtain the potential doomsday devices which lie at the site of each.